

# JAKE HYDE

Software Engineer

## C

+1 (917) 743-2090



jhyde@me.com



https://github.com/jakemeout



https://www.linkedin.com/in/jacobhyde

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JAVASCRIPT, RUBY, RUBY ON RAILS, GIT, SQL, HTML, CSS, REACT, REDUX, NODE, POSTGRES, HEROKU, BOOTSTRAP

#### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School | Full Stack Software Engineering Immersive, 2020

University at Albany | Electronic Music and Media Bachelor of Arts, 2010

#### **HOBBIES**

Writing and playing music, Hiking, Exploring NY, reading/watching Sci-Fi

## **PROFILE**

Full stack developer with a passion for innovation and building seamless user experiences. Recent experience developing full stack applications at the Flatiron school, 2+ years of managing internally built employee productivity tools, and 5+ years of IT technical experience.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Program Manager Tech, Uber — 2018-2020

Acted as scrum master and implemented agile frameworks for internal product development teams.

Supported 6 internal products such as Corp IAM to Recruiting tools as intermediary between front-line technical support and Engineering prioritization.

Managed stakeholder relationships, feature intake, product communication and organized development rollouts.

Collaborated on product enhancements, product operational processes, and QA.

Served as technical lead for vendor integrations support.

## HelpDesk Technician, Milestone Facebook & Uber - 2017-2018

Primary escalation point for frontline support team via onsite, Jira, and chat.

Deployed automated in-house tools to clients through endpoint management systems such as Chef, and Munki.

Managed, supported, and provisioned business application in a cloud-based environment.

Updated Service Desk processes, run-books, and leadership documentation in Atlasssian Confluence pages.

### Project Coordinator, Enjoy - 2015-2017

Coordinated launching new products and campaigns for www.enjoy.com.

Conducted user experience testing to optimize customer engagement with seasonal campaigns and flows.

Collaborated across teams to capture analytics, triage bugs, and execute improvements for higher engagement.

Coordinated changes in pricing (for e-commerce sales) with procurement and logistics teams.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### KickApp - React, Redux, Baseweb, Rails, Postgres, Stripe API, JWT

A platform to connect users with an app idea to developers where one can post an idea, and have the idea voted, sponsored, saved, or claimed by a developer to build.

- Implemented full user authentication and authorization flow with JWT and Bcrypt.
- Customized integration with Stripe to allow users to sponsor ideas.

## 

Provides users the ability to search a location, get driving directions, and receive realtime COVID data from New York Times to provide risk assessment of an area.

- Built a scheduled task to pull NYT data daily to update backend API, providing fast up-to-date COVID risk assessment in frontend.
- Integrated Google Maps Directions, Places, and Autocomplete API for navigation.